[Music] in September 2023 I flew from Sydney
to Iceland for a real bucket list motorcycle
tour with Local Company ride with locals upon
arrival the first thing we had to do was pick
our bike they've got 350s 450s and 700 cc bikes
and even though I ride a 701 back in in Sydney
I opted for the lighter 350 which I loved then we
had a briefing by the owner skoly he told us a bit
about where we're going to be riding and what to
expect and after that we jumped on our bikes and
we headed out because you never know what that's
going to comment there were eight of us in the
group but what we didn't realize at the time was
that before the end of day one one of our party
was going to be off with a broken leg and then
after day two their partner was also going to
leave the trip so we spent most of the trip with
seabus so here's the plan for day one we started
at SOS and we had about 50k of tarmac and then we
hit the dirt and we had um a lovely first day's
ride and we ended up in a hut called [Music] rupan
the terrain on day one sort of started yeah pretty
average but it just got better and better as we
approached the highlands the volcanic surface
that we're riding on is quite amazing it's quite
soft so you slide a lot but it never seems to give
way I never had my back wheel and my tires slide
out on me and it's just so much fun it's just kind
of like the bikes bouncing around it's sliding
around but yet there's so much traction it's
kind of it's a strange surface but it's probably
the best most enjoyable surface I've ever ridden
on
now this is where the accident happened you
can see on the right hand side of the track
there's a sort of rut and a wash out which
is easy enough to avoid but Steven got his
front wheel stuck in it and the bike came down
on top of him and at the bottom of a hill we
were taking selfies in front of the waterfall
and enjoying just the beautiful panoramas and
we didn't realize that Steven was actually
pretty bad badly hurt at the top of the hill
with a broken leg Steven had fallen at the top
of the hill which was very exposed and it was
cold and windy so the first thing we did is
we took him down to the bottom of the hill
and found some shelter even down here at the
bottom of the hill it was still pretty cold
and windy it was going to take some time before
the support vehicle reached us so we decided to
actually put Steven on the back of a bike and
double him to a nearby Hut where he could stay
stay warm while we're [Music] waiting at least
Steven was now warm as we waited for the support
vehicle which took him into Hospital look happy
and determined that he'd broken his leg in three
places the wind continued to build that afternoon
so we beelined it to our Hut for the night
[Music]
it was a beautiful little Hut on the banks of
a river just set in this gorgeous Valley so we
settled into our first first of five nights in
the mountain hut it had been an eventful day
one it was day two and it was windy and
wet so we didn't have high expectations
about this day's riding the guides planned
some local things to see so we're going to
check out a couple of waterfalls and
some volcanic [Music] craters [Music]
while the wind stayed on and off during
the day the rain actually stopped and
it was pretty nice riding riding up
to the volcanic craters was pretty
[Music]
impressive
[Music] we came to our first sort of longer
water crossing and the guides gave us pretty
0:04:59.560,1193:02:47.295
[Music]
clear instructions take it nice and slowly well
Nick didn't follow instructions I'm not going to
bloody wait for you then Nick had to do the
walk of shame and push his bikes through the
water turned out Nick had
drowned the bike thanks Nick
no luckily the guides were well
prepared they had spare oil so we
did a quick oil change on the side of
the road and and we got going [Music]
again the views were just incredible it's almost
like around every Bend was
just an impossibly beautiful
Panorama and riding through the lava Fields it
just felt like we're on another planet at times
[Music]
[Music] play out let me get out behind
you [Music]
[Music]
lots of time to just stop and take in
the view take a few photos it really was
beautiful
is and after a wonderful day two of riding we
headed back to our Hut for another wonderful
meal but tonight we had movie night and we were
going to watch Eurovision with Will Ferell and
highly recommended to anyone that wants to get
some insight into Icelandic culture who was to
hear your vision [Applause] song yeah ding here
we [Music] go on day three the wind eased and it
was looking like better weather so we rode from
our Hut up to an incredible waterfall called hios
and another amazing Valley that I cannot even
attempt to pronounce and then we went to the
thermal Springs at L mana laga and then finally
drove to our new Hut for the [Music] night
[Music]
when we got to hios get closer Nick we
were greeted by just an incredible sight is
scary being right on the edge of this
incredible Canyon with just not one
but three spectacular waterfalls
was quite mind-blowing [Music]
then we rode to this incredible Canyon
the name I'm not even going to attempt to
[Music]
pronounce
after Nick's Escapade of drowning
the bike on day two the guides were
taking no chances and making sure that
Nick wasn't going to drown any more
bikes it was too cold and too windy for us
we didn't want to take all that gear off and
get in the springs and then get geared up
again but I ended up staying here with my
family a few days later and my boys sunk
quite a few beers that evening in the hot
springs then we took a route up into the
mountains and I don't think anyone was
expecting it but it started snowing
and the snow just got heavier and
and heavier and the next thing you
know we were riding in our Winter
[Music]
[Music] Wonderland and while all of us
had ice and snow head to toe we just
loved the experience especially
coming from Australia it's not
something you get very often to
ride through snow and a [Music]
[Music]
blizzard
we made our way to a new Hut
for night three and it was in
just the most beautiful Valley and
it was a an incredible Hut we had
the Hut to ourselves and it was just
a stunning stunning Vista to wake up
to day four and this is where things
went to a whole new level in terms of
beauty we rode from our beautiful
hutner Valley through the volcanic
region of Heckler and ended up on the
other side of the national [Music]
park the weather was fantastic
the wind had dropped and we knew
we were going to have a really great day riding
now in my adventure writing in Australia I've
seen all kinds of warning signs but never one
for volcanic eruption so that was a new one for me
we were now riding towards the volcano Heckler and
the riding was fast it was flowing and we all sort
of just got into a Groove and just had a great
time the clouds were quite low and
it created quite a sort of dramatic
landscape it was just really hard
to describe what it was like to ride
through well Nick and I both ride 700 cc bikes
in Australia we were both just loving the light
little 350s and it was just so much fun to
slide them around on this incredible [Music]
surface
0:15:58.600,1193:02:47.295
[Music]
as the day went on the scene reges
got more and more spectacular and we
all were just loving the riding
more and more day four was just
[Music] amazing in terms of terrain we had
a bit of everything on day four there was
sort of slower more Rocky trails and then we
had the highspeed flowy Trails we even had
um snow riding and some sort of steep hills I
found myself using a term in Iceland impossibly
beautiful and it really is just describes
what I was seeing it's almost like around
every turn around every bend the scenery was
just impossibly beautiful and I'll finish off
day for with some examples of what the riding was
like and and what the scy was like it was [Music]
[Music] mindblowing [Music]
[Music] like after Nick drowned the bike on day
two our guide was taking no Chances with Nick
he was giving him remedial Crossing advice you
know what it's like when you're riding and all
of a sudden you just sort of become one with
the bike you're you're relaxed you're riding
about as well as you can ride the terrain is
amazing the track is fantastic the weather is
incredible and the scenery is just mind-blowing
you kind of get into this euphoric mode and
that's how I felt on um day four it was just
probably the best riding I have ever [Music]
[Music]
done oh he
[Music] go
[Music]
we finished day four at a new Hut and this Hut was
situated right on the edge of
this most beautiful beautiful
Canyon day five was the highlight of the trip
for me because we were going to ride in the
Black Desert our route today was a circular
route through the Black Desert but the SES
that we saw were just mind-blowing baby the
weather was perfect and we were all really
excited about the ride today actually it's
probably worth just introducing our three
amazing guides that we had on this trip
we had MGI who was fantastic secondly we
had Modesta and then finally we had AA um
all three guyses were just the best hats
off to them we set off under beautiful
blue skies and made our way to the Black
Desert the colors of Iceland
are amazing the bright greens
against the black soil just make for an incredible
power we stopped at this beautiful
little hikers Hut and just checked
out the view and just took some
time to um take it all in like a
lake the pace definitely picked up
on day five I think we were all just
really comfortable on the bikes and on
the terrain and we were having [Music]
fun and we came to this really beautiful Lake
and we just um spent some time riding up and
around it and onto this little Peninsula
and the views around this Lake were just
mind-blowing I really appreciated
the stops that we made because you
know often when you're riding along
quickly on the dirt bikes the views
can just fly past you and just stop and look
around and take these views in it is pretty
special the next stop was the Black Desert and
I was really looking forward to this cuz I don't
know I love these vast open desolate areas I just
find them really f fting oh yeah that view is just
awesome look at that the Black Desert I'd seen a
few pictures of it and I knew it was going to be
something special and it didn't disappoint you
know some people might find it just Barren and
not attractive but I don't know it was incredible
to me I love just this desolate bleakness it was
[Music] stunning and as we started climbing up the
mountain there was steam coming off the ground and
I wasn't sure if it was steam from rain or whether
it was from volcanic activity but it was pretty
cool and as we approached the top of the
mountain all of a sudden the views just
unfolded in front of us and it really sort of
took our Breath Away by the vastness of [Music]
it
[Music]
this was a great place for our lunch stop
and here we just enjoyed this pretty special
view then as we left the mountain
toop we drove back down and we just
had this amazing view across the
Black Desert that we had ridden
across I think this will give you a
real sense for how amazing it [Music]
is [Music] wiser the r is [Music]
down the Black Desert did not [Music] disappoint
that afternoon we rode pretty hard and we rode
pretty fast and it was a a long day but
boy it was a a beautiful day it was just
so spectacular and [Music] enjoyable
without a doubt day five was my favorite
[Music] day [Music]
[Applause] [Music]
by the end of the day we were hungry we were
tired we were thirsty but boy what an amazing day
five
it was the final day of our tour but Iceland
still had a few gems to share with us today
we made our way back to SOS from our
heart but we rode through some pretty
incredible [Music] Landscapes but I thought
I'd start the day by screwing around with
my drone and capturing some images of these
gorgeous Canyons right behind our [Music] Hut
they have a saying in Iceland that if you don't
like the weather wait 5 minutes and it'll change
and that's very true but unfortunately
in our case it sort of changed for the
worse the clouds came in and it created
a pretty moody mysterious atmosphere but
on this last day we came across some scenery
which is just as good as anything we'd seen
on the previous 5 days this waterfall was
pretty cool to R [Music] across we then
rode back out into another Black Desert
again I just love the starkness of this
landscape like check this out a perfect green
cone just coming out of this
Black Desert how cool is that
[Music]
w
the guides had one more little finale up
their sleeves they took us down into this
beautiful little canyon where we could just
ride along the river and it was um a lot of
fun
[Music]
I always find myself just reflecting on the
trip on the last day and my reflections of
this trip were you know while Australia may
have more adventurous murder bite riding I
can't imagine anywhere in the world that
has more beautiful riding than Iceland the
landscape is just stunningly stunningly
beautiful in fact I've already signed up
for another trip next year I'm going to
the West fiords in June and as for the
tour operator you know I'm not big for tours
but this trip was just brilliantly organized
the people that I was riding with were
a lot of fun the guides fantastic the
equipment totally reliable and um it was
faultless I would highly recommend them to
[Music]
anybody